Runze (Martin) Yi

Tel: 416-357-9663 | E-mail: ryi9@uwo.ca | linkedin/in/runze-yi-395869211

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION

Data Analysis & Visualization: Strong problem-solving skills and analytic mindset, familiar with analyzing large datasets, experienced in creating engaging and informative reports that drive business actions.

Interpersonal & Communication: Demonstrated ability to effectively communicate project updates and roadblocks to stakeholders, proactively identifying and resolving conflicts in a fast-paced environment.

Technical Skills: Proficient in using SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Python, R and Microsoft Office, extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, Typescript and PHP. Machine learning with Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning. Familiarity and experience with PyTorch and TensorFlow.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Analytics, specialization in Artificial Intelligence, GPA3.7/4.0 Western University, London, Ontario	Sept. 2022 - Aug. 2023
Bachelor of Computing (Hons.) , Specialization in Data Analytics, GPA3.7/4.3 Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario	Sept. 2017 - June 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE

Decision Support Coop

Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga Ontario

May 2023 - Aug. 2023

- Documented and moved-to-production the Daily Census prediction and ALC & Long Term Patients dashboard
- Data hunted internally and externally for additional metrics to use in introducing new features to the Daily Census prediction, and took the lead in implementing a machine learning model to predict admission and discharge volumes
- Worked closely with Privacy to secure the safety of using Personal Health Information from SQL/Power BI to Python
- Helped in filtering the data quality issue in the 'Time to Inpatient Bed', one of the most crucial metrics in THP
- Collected, cleaned and analyzed data to produce high quality data-driven insights, designed interactive visualizations, and discussed the findings with customers to make modifications based on their feedback
- Effectively communicated, managed multiple projects while having to shift from priorities, and exceeded partner expectations. Consistently received positive feedback from both internally and externally

Data Analyst

Kaiweizhongda International Education Co., Ltd. Guangzhou, China

July 2021 - July 2022

- Communicated directly with business stakeholders to finalize the business requirement and analytic solutions
- Conducted in-depth data analysis using various data collection methods. Efficiently identified, processed, and analyzed raw information by leveraging SQL and building monthly report using Tableau that helped to develop a strategy
- Created the daily KPI report that ensured tracking of key metrics and identified areas for improvement for mobile and web applications
- Designed analytical model and improved customer conversion by 7%

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Flight Delay Prediction

- Predicted whether a flight will be delayed with data on time, origination, destination and distance of travel
- Analyzed and pre-processed data to perform Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) on effects of individual factors
- Implemented a logistic regression model using Python and achieved 81% accuracy

Machine Learning Based Channel Quality Prediction for 5G Cellular Networks

- Predicted 5G signal quality of a single cellular receiver of 10 milliseconds later
- Collected data from Siradel Smart City over a street in Toronto for over 10000 milliseconds
- Trained a Long Short Term Memory(LSTM) neural network to perform time series forecasting with low MSE

WHO Life Expectancy

- Predict life expectancy given the country, demographic variables, income composition, mortality rates, immunization and human development
- Cleaned data and validated statistical model assumptions while performing variable selection
- Implemented linear regression model in R and achieved adjusted R² of 0.87